So, Fable 5 is officially back in the
wild, but realistically, it's only going
to be around for a few more days until
it's no longer available in your max
plan, and you have to like pay for the
extra credits. And so, I think there's
really two things that you can do in
this situation. Number one is that you
can just do a bunch of random and
try to like oneshot designs on throwaway
projects, or number two, you can do the
three things that I'm about to show you
in this video. And so the first thing up
on this list is improving our skills. So
Fable 5 is really great at understanding
context and intent. It is significantly
better than Opus 4.8 at that. And so we
should be using this unstoppable power
that was so powerful the US government
had to tell people they couldn't use it.
We want to use that in order to improve
the things that outside of the context
of having access to Fable, we will still
want to use on a daily basis. How can we
use this to improve the things that are
our daily drivers? And so what we'll go
through as an example here is my go-to
market skill library, which shameless
plug, you get if you're inside of my
paid community, link in the description
below. But inside of this, we have like
a few different skills that help you
pick out like your goto market strategy.
So, what's the actual channel strategy?
How are you going to position yourself
against other options? How are you going
to determine your pricing? Decide the
structure of your landing page, like
write the copy for the landing page, all
of those types of things. And I want to
make sure obviously since I I give this
skill to people that it's as dialed in
as it can be. And so, this is a good
example of where we can run this type of
audit. So, we can pop into our command
line here. Now, if you want to know how
to use Fable, it doesn't show up by
default in the dropown. So you can just
type /model fable and that will set
fable to the uh to the active model. And
so I'm going to run this skill audit
skill which is just a custom skill that
I created to audit other skills very
meta. And in this case, I'm just giving
it like a very generic open-ended prompt
where I wanted to look for general areas
of improvement, particularly in the
context of like this skill library where
it comes to copywriting and and like
landing pages because this is something
that I think a lot of people rely on to
be done well, especially if you don't
have a background in in marketing. I've
codified this thing with all of my
experiences having run like successful
marketing agencies before and building
and selling apps. And so I wanted to
make sure that it's like really dialed
in and that it's successfully
translating those like resources and
rules that I've created so that they're
actually being enforced properly by the
skill. And then I just want to make sure
that there's no other areas inside of
the other skills that feed into this one
that are potentially causing issues. So
we just want to make sure this thing is
super dialed in. Now you can apply this
same approach to pretty much anything.
last time Fable was accessible to us. I
use this to dial in my actual like
development skills. So I have like a
custom plugin that I use personally that
combines Spectri driven development and
the best of all of the libraries I use.
So Compound Engineering, Ora
Superpowers, all of those different
skill libraries that we all know and
love. I've taken what I like from all of
them and combined them into like one
system that works for me. And I used
Fable to help me do that and help dial
it in and make sure all the pieces were
connecting properly, making
modifications to those skills where I
needed to. That's like a really strong
use case that you can run too. And so
the way that I've configured this skill,
it's going to go through and try to like
ground itself in in context. So it's
asking me a lot of questions about like
what specifically I want audited. And so
in this case, I've gone through and I've
answered all of these questions based on
like what I think could be improved from
the skill because there's always room
for improvement. And now we're kicking
it off and letting it letting it go. All
right, guys. So, this thing is done now
and we can kind of walk through what its
findings were. So, in this case, it says
that the actual like process of how this
actually moves through and like the
different pieces that we have are
genuinely strong. And so, I mean, this
makes sense. I I used this or like
codified this based on like real world
processes and used opus to build these
things. But the the issue comes in with
like these little details. And I think
that's something that Fable's actually
really good with. It can understand the
larger picture, but it can really audit
like these smaller, seemingly smaller
like edge cases where important details
would otherwise slip through the cracks.
In this example, we have like a lot of
these inputs that we know we take time
to build like the brand voice and
customer language and like design
specifics and they aren't being properly
translated downstream to other phases.
And so that's one big piece. And then
the second piece is that part of what
the skill is is meant to be able to do.
It will tell you like the the sections
that your page should have in order to
be like a a high converting, you know,
SAS or mobile app landing page. But what
it doesn't necessarily do well is
translate into something that like you
could just pass this as a spec to claude
code and it will like build you
something that's like genuinely
memorable from as like a landing page.
And so it can produce copy really well,
but it there's nothing that's like
pushing it into this like wow factor
state. And so in this case, it's found a
few different issues that could be like
driving that. Number one is again these
seams that we talked about where like
details that we've decided aren't making
their way through. A second thing, which
I think is a really valuable convention,
I I do this with other skills that I
have for building, especially when I'm
working with claw design, is building
like handoff systems. So if you were to
think of tools like claw design versus,
you know, other tools like Google Stitch
or Figma or Pencil.dev or whatever, they
all have like different ways of
prompting them that work better. And so
having little adapters that can take a
plan and convert it into whatever tool
you want to work with is super valuable.
And so one of the failure modes I think
in this case is that I'm pasting in like
a ton of context to to claw design and
it's not what it needs. like it needs
that adapter step so that we can format
everything in the way that it needs to
be for design tools specifically to be
able to work with it. And so again, the
the reason this is better than something
like Opus is that I've already run this
audit several times with Opus and every
time we make a skill, it's attempting to
optimize this piece, right? Like is the
process strong? But it's not going to
the level of looking at like all of
these like seemingly smaller individual
things that can force this deviation
from what you as a user like actually
most likely wanted. So if we were to
think of this concept of like a
motivational intent or like a goal, it's
a lot better at seeing the goal through
the details of things and taking those
things through to completion. So this is
pretty a pretty awesome audit that we've
done. Again, in this context, I would
apply the same exact thing to like any
dev tooling that you use or really any
sort of skills that you like to use on a
on a regular basis that you're thinking
like, you know, sometimes it's good,
sometimes it's not, but it's never
wowing me. This type of workflow is
going to be super super super valuable
for you. And so now we have a very
concrete plan. And the nice thing is
that we don't necessarily need fail to
implement this. we could implement it in
in sub agents with Opus. Have Fable be
the orchestrator. Kind of like a sky is
the limit type of situation. So for me,
skills are like a daily driver. It's
what I use probably the most. I often
will create like my own versions based
on things I found in like open source
that I want dialed in for me. And so
taking the time to like audit those
things and make them super locked in is
I think one of the most valuable things
you could possibly do with your time.
But what about the features that we
would actually build with these types of
skills? So if you're not a trained
engineer by background, but I mean
even if you are, using these tools to
audit through things that you have
already built is an incredibly valuable
thing to do. So in this project, we have
something that has been driving me a
little bit crazy. This is the design for
this this mobile app that I've been
working on. And what happened was I
started adding in these agent loops. So
when I built the first iteration of this
thing, it made a few language model
calls, but it wasn't anything crazy. And
then I started adding in and building my
own agent loop. And that is where the
bug started. And so I've been working
through this trying to fix the thing,
but I want to make sure that it is 100%
dialed in because we're getting ready to
take this thing to market. And so I need
to, you know, rubber needs to meet the
road and we need to make sure this thing
is actually bulletproof. And so good a
time as any to test out how Fable can
audit what we have built. And so again,
we're going to come down into our
project and we're going to run this
again custom command that I have called
zoom out and think. And so I use this
type of skill when I'm in a situation
where we're just running into the same
issues over and over and over and over
again. and it seems like we're just
we're too much in the nuance and the
system needs to be able to look at
things from a higher level and really
try to understand like what is the root
cause of this at like the system level.
So instead of looking at a specific bug
and just constantly trying to patch it
and then other bugs pop out like based
on what I am trying to do with this
project, what are the core issues that
we need to actually think through and
resolve and so we have fable 5 going out
and running this zoom out and think
command. Okay, so this thing is now
finished running through. So it
basically read through everything in the
project and then it did a web search to
find like what are the modern best
practices for like this specific domain
which in this case is like constructing
your own like agent loop like a a react
loop here and so we can read through
then and see like what exactly did it
find and I'll talk a little bit about
like where I think this is a lot
different from the type of analysis you
would get with a tool like opus. So how
the system actually works. So it has
gone through now and broken down like
precisely how the the system itself
functions. We don't need to read through
this entire thing. It's specific to this
project. But we have this homegrown
react loop that we run. And so it can go
through it can accept a message from the
user. It has a bunch of tools that it
can use. And the the fundamental thing
here that I I think is the core issue is
that the state of things, right? So if
we're having this conversation from like
our app in this case back to the server,
the the state of the thing is only
living really on the client side and and
that's going to be a big problem. And
this is something that like Opus
entirely missed. So I I've gone through
so many of these debugging exercises
running this exact same command with a
tool like Opus. And again, it's always
finding these like like duct tape
band-aid type of solutions. And that's
why we have so many commits because like
every time we patch something, we're
just patching that thing and then the
next time you run into an issue, it's
like, okay, well now I need to patch
whatever that thing is too because I'm
not solving for what the underlying
problem actually is. So it's grounding
itself in how the system actually works
and then it's moving to like what is the
real ask that we have of this. And so in
this case, if we were to read through
this, I want the agent to feel coherent
across a conversation. It needs to be
able to like log meals for people, do
planning properly, clarify ambiguous
asks or food items, commit those
changes, allow users to correct them.
And we need to do this in a way where
every single time we want to handle one
of these things, we're not just patching
patching patching patching patching our
way through the entire thing. Just
making all of these individual fixes
that are not fixing the actual core
underlying problem. And again, this is
something that Opus has like failed to
diagnose even with me pointing it to the
fact that I think the loop is the
problem. I've I've kicked off many chats
with Opus saying, "Hey, I think that
this loop that we have is fundamentally
what the issue is. It's not using tools
correctly. It's not remembering what a
person said. It's not kicking off things
in response to like a user's reply
properly. Like it's not doing any of
that, and it needs to be." and it it
kind of failed to find these these types
of issues. And so the core thing here is
that the the loop on the server side is
stateless. Like it doesn't know what
happened before, but the the
conversation isn't. And that that is
like fundamentally what the issue is now
inside of this project. And so it has
basically broken down for us like the
the specifics of that. And so one last
thing again is that like what is the
difference between something like this
and Opus? we like came to a lot of these
conclusions already in research that was
being done. So when I was using Opus
kicking off all these like sprawling
research agents to try to figure out
like what could be the cause we came to
conclusions about like the interrupt
pattern and how users need to be able to
interact with the system. like we we
decided some of those things but opus or
I mean can't blame everything on the
model the human driving the process with
opus like not all of the patterns that
needed to be there were actually
implemented now if you're a user that
just lets a lot of things go hands off
which if we're being honest a lot of
people do that these are the types of
issues you can you can run into right
when you're doing things that like are a
little bit more basic I think you tend
not to either notice them or the things
are a lot more straightforward and so
they don't really rear their head and it
doesn't become a problem. But if you're
starting to get into like I don't know
like agent patterns and like building
things that are kind of complicated.
This is why you need to like slow down
when you're doing spec processes and
like make sure all of the bases are are
actually covered. And so we're going to
summarize all that down like what is
kind of like the needle in the haystack
thing that it found. And again that's
something that Fable's really good at.
What is that? Like that really seemingly
obscure but actually really important to
the system working type of thing. We
need to have a checkpointer that
persists the state on the server. So
when it's interrupted and it needs a
response from the user that it it
remembers everything that's happened so
far and then the user replying is just
like continuing the execution and it
actually has the full context of what
has happened before. And so
fundamentally we have this issue where
we're actually relying on like the
client side to do too much of the
orchestration of things, right? Like the
client should just be responsible for
rendering things ultimately and it's
doing too much of the orchestration
which it shouldn't be doing. And so this
is obviously a situation where like we
need to make some sort of like
meaningful update to how this works so
that it's like actually a proper agent
loop. And so in this case, this is a
situation where I would use Fable to
like actually build my specs. And that
is exactly what I'm going to do. And so
I'm going to come down here and I'm
going to tell it use opensp spec propose
to create new specs to fix 1 2 3. The
implementation will take place with a
lesser model like opus. So make sure the
plan carries forward motivational intent
and all critical details of what needs
to be implemented and why. So again
wrapping all this up, I think Fable is
is really good at auditing things. You
know, in in the case of my project, I
was trying to build a loop in a way
where honestly like I I probably wasn't
in the loop as much as I should have
been. and this thing has gone a little
bit sideways and it's not so far down
the road that it's not reversible. It's
just we're going to have to like delete
a lot of work that we already did, but
at least now we know like precisely what
the problem is. And it's very clear to
me reading this that the the system
understands what the problem is. And so
now again, we're kicking off proposals
and we'll be able to like systematically
work through this thing and build it
even if we're not using Fable, right?
Even if we're using something like like
Opus to actually do the implementation,
we're going to rely on Fable to actually
build that plan out. So, this is all
well and good, but what about if we want
to build like net new things, especially
again like in a system like this where
there's a lot of different pieces and we
want to make sure it all integrates
properly together. So, the last thing
that I really love using Fable for,
whether it's in the context of like
building features, even for knowledge
work, I think a lot of people when Fable
first came out said it wasn't good at
knowledge work. I think that's complete
I think it's really good at
it. But either way, it's very good at
taking in a lot of different context
from different places. This could be
like your background knowledge on
something, what you want to accomplish,
notes you've taken on something in the
past, your ideas for a feature, whatever
it is. It's really good at taking that,
understanding the goal and the intent
behind it, and then going out doing a
bunch of other research and like
properly marrying those two things
together. And so that is what we're
going to kick off here. So like this
entire process of like doing research,
exploring an idea, ideulating around it,
executing through like the full life
cycle, it's really good at doing that
compared with again tools like Opus. And
so if I were going to do something like
this again with a tool like Opus or even
like ChatC,
you would have to go through and really
break this thing down into like a ton of
different parts. even from like the
research and exploration phase, you
would need to research all of those
things individually and then attempt to
like bring them back together. And that
can be like a little bit of an arduous
process. And so we're going to see how
well Opus or sorry, we're going to see
how well Fable can do that just like
kind of vanilla out of the box. And so
just so you guys know like exactly what
we're like trying to plan through in
this one. We're now like in that like
first thing that we went through with
like the feature brainstorming. We're
trying to resolve how all of this stuff
actually like functions on the server
side like on the back end, but we need
to then be able to like specifically
stream these events through to the front
end as they're happening so that we can
even like surface this type of stuff,
right? So like the UI that we're
building needs to be like tightly
coupled to what the backend can actually
surface for us so that all of this stuff
like can actually render in in a smart
way. And so this is basically the UI
that this streaming is going to allow us
to to enable and that is why we are
working on it. This is one of the last
things we need to dial in before the app
can actually get launched. So just to
put like pictures to what I say when I'm
saying like streaming the events back
and like streaming the tokens. Streaming
the tokens means that like this is going
to type out as it appears, right? So,
we're not it's not just going to pop up
in one block. It's going to actually
stream the tokens to us. And then we
need to also like stream the events that
are happening on the server. So, when
tools are being called, when it's
hitting like important markers and
things are happening, we want to be able
to send that to the back to the front
end as well. All right, guys. So, this
thing fully finished through and it
planned out the entire system. there's
like a lot of really nice research like
finding out like what are the potential
like caveats like what's actually the
real grounded state of things and all of
that. But one thing that I wanted to do
is try to think through like where is
this actually different from what you
would get out of a tool like like Opus.
And so I went through and I actually
kicked off the same exact thing. The
only difference was I said you can't go
look at past chats. I didn't want to
read that and come up with the solution.
And then I gave it the same exact
prompt. Okay. I gave it the same exact
same exact prompt. It went through, it
came up with, you know, all of the
things that we would probably go through
and and start implementing on unless we
were really spending time to challenge
through. And so what I did was I moved
through that and then I had uh Fable
look through it and tell me like based
on what we just came to the conclusion
about, what did that other chat get
wrong? And again, they had the same
exact context and the same exact command
to kick this thing off. Again, the only
difference is that in one I said like,
"Hey, you can't read other chats." What
is actually the difference? And this is
important because it's going to give us
a sense of like where Fable is super
valuable and give you an understanding
of based on like the apps you have now
and you want to really make use of this
like now while you still can, what are
the types of like heavy problems you
should be putting it on. So, I had it
categorized into things that are like
dangerously wrong like they would really
drive a bad implementation. And so the
first thing is that Opus was about to
just like reintroduce a new class of
bugs that we had already fixed. And so
based on like the the way that like
events are going to get emitted and like
shown to us in the front end, it was
completely wrong about how to actually
do that. And so this is where we get
into those things where like you're
constantly running into the same errors
in like a slightly different form. This
is like the type of thing where that
would happen. We're just relying on
Opus. think it's smart. It goes out and
it's just doing the same things over and
over again in slightly different ways
and just reintroducing bugs. That's part
of the reason why Fable's really great
because it can think through these
things in like a way that's pretty
impressive, I think. So, it found a few
of these things. Another one that was
pretty big is like the way that it's
planning to do it is like simply going
to to break. And so in this case like
what happens when a user actually like
interrupts things or it pauses like what
actually happens in terms of like the
agent responses and things like that. It
was going to implement this thing like
completely backwards. It also had some
things that were just like factually
incorrect about like what Superbase was
actually capable of or not capable of
doing. Now, something like this, the
things in this category, I think these
are things where like you could
obviously go through and point it at
like tools like Context 7 or like
forcing it to go out and and look at
documentation and things like that. But
again, this is something that of Fable
was able to just do on its own without
that extra direction because it knows
that it like really needs to resolve
this thing. So, I think the way that it
plans and executes on things that are
important to the goal is really good.
And so a few other things like it found
some structural issues with with what it
was going to be implementing and like
what it thought was like the core of the
thing and the most authoritative piece
of the system that like needed to be
done well and it didn't actually handle
that properly. So again, we would have
structural issues if we move through and
just implement it blindly with what with
what it was outputting for us. And then
there's some smaller things where like
it didn't actually explore other
relevant pieces of the the codebase. So
all in all, Fable 5 when it comes to
like I would categorize this as like
more complex brainstorming like trying
to implement a server side streaming in
the context of our app from scratch.
Fable was significantly better at doing
this and I'm going to actually move
through after this video is over and
implement all of this. So all in all,
we're only going to have this for a few
more days. I'm recording this on July
2nd and this is only going to be
available to July 7th. though I thought
I saw in my in my UI somewhere that it
was going to be till July 9th. So I
could be wrong about that. And so again
after this is over it's going to go to
like a usage based thing and this model
is super expensive. So I don't think
it's going to be reasonable for the
majority of people to use this on usage
credits. So I highly recommend you go
through and think about either like one
or all three of these things that I've
gone through in this in this video. So
like improving our skills, auditing
existing features that we already have
in place that we need to make like more
robust and better or using this to
brainstorm some of those more like
ambitious features that seemed like they
were going to be a little bit too
complicated for you to maybe do and
seeing if Fable can help you bridge that
gap. Now, if you want help with like any
of this type of stuff, like I said
earlier, I do have a a paid community
that is growing and there's a bunch of
like custom skills and plugins and
people are actually building awesome
stuff in there and getting paid for
them, which is nice. So, if you like
this video and you don't subscribe yet,
make sure to subscribe. But that is it
for this one. I will see you in the next